A snowman longs to break out of his snow globe.
Knick Knack is a animation, family, comedy film directed by John Lasseter.
Life on a shelf as a snowman trapped in a snow-globe blizzard can become wearing,
especially when you're surrounded by knickknacks from sunnier locales.
When the jaded snowman finally breaks free of his glass
house, his vacation plans are cut short.
Knick Knack is a 1989 American animated short film produced by
Pixar that was written and directed by John Lasseter.
The short is about a snow globe snowman who wants to join the
other travel souvenirs in a summer-themed party.
However, the glass dome that surrounds him prevents him from doing so, thus
leading to his many tries to break out of his snow globe.
Knick Knack is Pixar's fourth short and the final short produced
during the company's tenure as a hardware company.
It was also the final Pixar short film released before the
company's first feature-length film Toy Story.
The short stands out from Lasseter's other early short films at Pixar
in its reliance on pure comedy to drive the story.
It was inspired by Tom and Jerry, Looney Tunes, and the
work of animators Chuck Jones and Tex Avery.
Lasseter and his wife, Nancy, collected snow globes and also enjoyed souvenirs from
distant places and those elements made their way into the short as well.
Singer Bobby McFerrin improvised the a cappella vocal jazz soundtrack to the film while
watching a rough cut which was eventually left unchanged in its final edition.
Knick Knack debuted at the 1989 SIGGRAPH convention in
Boston, Massachusetts and was presented in 3D.
The short has enjoyed positive reviews since its debut and has
been screened as a part of numerous film festivals.
The short has now been associated with Finding Nemo, with a remastered version of the
short being shown before it in that film's original theatrical run.
The film explores themes of escape, snowman, snowglobes, short film.
The tone is lighthearted.